Guide to the Edward Bradford Titchener papers,1887-1940.
Titchener, Edward Bradford papers, 1887-1940
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Edward Bradford Titchener papers, 1887-1940.
14-23-545
Edward Bradford, Titchener 1867-1927
6.2 cubic ft.
Correspondence
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Largely correspondence presenting a picture of the professional status and interests of psychologist Edward Titchener, containing much information on fellow psychologists and psychology departments at other universities, as well as the struggle of psychology to establish itself as an academic discipline. There is also correspondence concerning the publication of THE AMERICAN JOURNAL OF PSYCHOLOGY and a bound typescript of Titchener's A BEGINNER'S PSYCHOLOGY (1915).
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor of Psychology, Cornell University.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Largely correspondence presenting a picture of the professional status and varied interests of a scholar of international reputation, and containing much information on fellow psychologists, psychology departments at other universities, and the struggle of psychology to establish itself as an academic discipline. Most of the correspondence is incoming, but carbon copies of Titchener's letters are available in large quantity from 1921 through 1927. There is also correspondence with colleagues and students concerning the research and writings of Titchener and his fellow psychologists and the publication of THE AMERICAN JOURNAL OF PSYCHOLOGY. It reveals as well as the high quality of work he demanded from his students and his interest in their careers; other letters include two from Walter Pater, his tutor at Oxford, and one from Sigmund Freud. Other items include a bound typescript of Titchener's A BEGINNER'S PSYCHOLOGY (1915), inscribed to Edwin Boring, other books by Titchener, pamphlets, and photographs.
Correspondents include Frank Angell, James R. Angell, J. W. Baird, J. Mark Baldwin, Edwin G. Boring, J. McKeen Cattell, Karl M. Dallenbach, John Dewey, Raymond Dodge, Samuel W. Fernberger, G. Stanley Hall, Edwin B. Holt, William James, Joseph Jastrow, Charles Judd, A. Kirschmann, Oswald Külpe, Christine Ladd-Franklin, Herbert Langfeld, Hugo Münsterberg, A. H. Pierce, Walter B. Pillsbury, Josiah Royce, Edmund Clark Sanford, Carl E. Seashore, E. L. Thorndike, R. A. Tsanoff, Howard C. Watson, John B. Watson, Louis N. Wilson, Howland Wood, Robert Yerkes, Harry P. Weld, and Paul T. Young.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Titchener, Edward Bradford,1867-1927; Angell, Frank.; Angell, James Rowland, 1869-; Baird, John Wallace, 1873-1919.; Baldwin, James Mark, 1861-1934.; Boring, Edwin Garrigues, 1886-1968.; Cattell, James McKeen, 1860-1944.; Dallenbach, Karl M. 1887-1971.; Dewey, John, 1859-1952.; Dodge, Raymond, 1871-; Fernberger, Samuel Weiller, 1887-; Franklin, Christine Ladd, 1847-1930.; Freud, Sigmund, 1856-1939.; Hall, G. Stanley(Granville Stanley), 1844-1924.; Holt, Edwin B.(Edwin Bissell), 1873-1946.; James, William, 1842-1910.; Jastrow, Joseph, 1863-1944.; Judd, Charles Hubbard, 1873-; Kirschmann, August, 1860-1932.; Külpe, Oswald, 1862-1915.; Langfeld, Herbert Sidney, 1879-1958.; Münsterberg, Hugo, 1863-1916.; Pater, Walter, 1839-1894.; Pierce, Arthur Henry, 1867-1914; Pillsbury, Walter Bowers, 1872-; Royce, Josiah, 1855-1916.; Sanford, Edmund Clark, 1859-1924.; Seashore, Carl E.(Carl Emil), 1866-1949.; Thorndike, Edward L.,(Edward Lee), 1874-1949.; Tsanoff, Radoslav Andrea, 1887-; Warren, Howard C.(Howard Crosby), 1867-1934.; Watson, John Broadus, 1878-1958.; Weld, Harry Porter, 1877-1958.; Wilson, Louis N., 1857-1937.; Wood, Howland.; Yerkes, Robert Mearns, 1876-1956.; Young, Paul Thomas, 1892-
Titles:
The American Journal of Psychology.
Subjects:
Psychology, Experimental.; Psychology--Research.; Psychology--Study and teaching.; Psychology--Study and teaching (Graduate); Psychologists.; Experimental psychologists.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
A paper guide to the collection, including descriptions of the contents of some of the correspondence, lists of letters by correspondent, and some item listings not included below, is available by clicking here. 4 MB PDF
CONTAINER LIST
- Correspondence
  - Price List of European & Palaearctic birds' eggs, 1888 (Box 1)
  - Arthur M. L. Jackson to EBT, 7/11/1889 (Box 1)
  - Arthur M. L. Jackson to EBT, 8/19/89 (Box 1)
  - Arthur M. L. Jackson to EBT, 12/18/89 (Box 1)
  - W. Wundt to EBT, in German, 8/14/89 (Box 1)
  - Price list of Asiatic birds' eggs, 1889 (Box 1)
  - Catalogue of Australian birds' eggs Catalogue of Birds Eggs, 1890 (Box 1)
  - A. (Sidgwick)? to EBT, 1/31/90 (Box 1)
  - F. A. Dixey to EBT, 6/16/90 (Box 1)
  - Francis Golet (?) to EBT, 8/17/90 (Box 1)
  - Postcard (?) to Oswald Kulpe, in German, 11/23/90 (Box 1)
  - Frank Finn to EBT, 12/1/90 (?) (Box 1)
  - Price List of European & Palaearctic birds' egg, 1890 (Box 1)
  - Price List, 1890 (Box 1)
  - Postcard to Pavlovic, Serbian teacher, in German, 1891 (Jan. 1) (Box 1)
  - W. Warde Fowler to EBT, 12/5/92 (Box 1)
  - Wm. E. Hammond I.O.U. to EBT, 2/14/93 (Box 1)
  - Harry Gordon White to EBT, 4/12/93 (Box 1)
  - Willard N. Clute to EBT, 4/19/93 (Box 1)
  - Price List of European & Palaearctic Birds' Egg, 1893 (Box 1)
  - John Stafford to EBT, 7/2/94 (Box 1)
  - R. W. Shufeldt to EBT, 8/18/94 (Box 1)
  - James R. Angell to EBT, 8/2/94 (Box 1)
  - Oswald Kulpe to EBT (orig. ALS in German; also typed translation - Xerox), 4/ll/95 (Box 1)
  - Oswald Kulpe to EBT (ALS and translation), 4/27/95 (Box 1)
  - James R. Angell to EBT, 10/8/96 (Box 1)
  - N. Swartzman (?) Sr. to EBT, 5/31/97 (Box 1)
  - John H. Harris (re use of T's "Outline"), 9/21/97, 10/13/97 (Box 1)
  - T. C. Karns, (re use of T's "Outline"), 10/7/97 (Box 1)
  - W. J. Carson, London, Qnt. (T's transl. Wundt's "Physiological Psychology"), 10/8/97 (Box 1)
  - William James to EBT, 5/6/99 (Box 1)
  - Receipt for subscription from "The Psychological Review" to EBT, March 1899 (Box 1)
  - William James to EBT, 5/21/99 (Box 1)
  - Receipt from "Science" to EBT, 5/22/99 (Box 1)
  - William James to EBT, 5/31/99 (Box 1)
  - P. A. Fist to EBT - Receipt for dues, 6/1/99 (Box 1)
  - C. M. Aitken to EBT, 8/22/99 (Box 1)
  - J. H. G. (?) to EBT (postcard), 8/28/99 (Box 1)
  - Bills forwarded to EBT, 9/1/99 (Box 1)
  - EBT to Stella Emily Sharp, 9/10, 9/23, 9/26/99 (Box 1)
  - Fritzsche Bros, to EBT, 10/6/99 (Box 1)
  - EBT to Stella Emily Sharp, 10/1/99 (Box 1)
  - EBT to Stella Emily Sharp, 11/9/99 (Box 1)
  - EBT to Stella Emily Sharp, 12/17/99 (Box 1)
  - Dr. J. Kodis (?) to EBT, 12/30/99 (Box 1)
  - 1900 (Box 1)
  - Dr. Kristian B. R. Aars (?), in German, 1/17/00 (Box 1)
  - G.F. Stout to EBT, 3/10/00 (Box 1)
  - A. R. Hill to EBT, 3/15/00 (Box 1)
  - F. Angell (?) to EBT, 3/19/00 (Box 1)
  - K. Dessau to EBT, 3/20/00 (Box 1)
  - Edward M. Traber to EBT, 3/21/00 (Box 1)
  - Henry S. Williams to EBT, 3/24/00 (Box 1)
  - Joseph B. Wun (?), Jr. to EBT, 3/24/00 (Box 1)
  - E. C. Sandford to EBT, 3/31/00 (Box 1)
  - B. H. Blackwell to EBT, 4/12/00 (Box 1)
  - 0. B. Wood to EBT, 4/12/00 (Box 1)
  - M. Denis (?) to EBT (postcard), 4/12/00 (Box 1)
  - Charles G. Wagner to EBT, 4/13/00 (Box 1)
  - Ed. M. Traber to EBT, 4/13/00 (Box 1)
  - John Winslow, M.D. to EBT, 4/16/00 (Box 1)
  - J. G. Schurman to EBT, 4/17/00 (Box 1)
  - George S. Brett to EBT, 4/18/00 (Box 1)
  - Nan Gilbert Seymour to EBT, 5/21/00 (Box 1)
  - Pillsbury Account ending:, 6/30/00 (Box 1)
  - Diagram & Notes, 8/31/00 (Box 1)
  - A. Schinz (?) to EBT, 9/29/00 (Box 1)
  - Dr. K. B. R. Aars (?), in German, 10/30/00 (Box 1)
  - Edmund Montgomery to EBT, 11/1100 (Box 1)
  - Osw. Kulpe (?) to EBT, in German, 12/13/00 (Box 1)
  - G. M. Whipple to EBT, 12/28/00 (Box 1)
  - 1901 (Box 1)
  - E. C. Sanford to Whipple - Postcard, 1/8/01 (Box 1)
  - L. H. W. to EBT - Postcard, 1/17/01 (Box 1)
  - From "The Atheneum, 1/26/01 (Box 1)
  - Pres. Schurman on need for new Physics Bldg., 1/29/01 (Box 1)
  - L. Burton (?) to EBT, 3/3/01 (Box 1)
  - Arthur Hall (Zeigler Electric Co.) to EBT, 3/7/01 (Box 1)
  - Arthur Hall (Zeigler Electric Co.) to EBT, 3/22/01 (Box 1)
  - Arthur Hall (Zeigler Electric Co.) to EBT, 4/1/01 (Box 1)
  - F. De Sarlo to EBT, in Italian, 4/3/01 (Box 1)
  - I. (?) Sully to EBT, 4/9/01 (Box 1)
  - Margaret K. Smith to EBT, 4/21/01 (Box 1)
  - J. Mc K. Cattell to EBT, 4/23/01 (Box 1)
  - J. G. Schurman to EBT, 5/2/01 (Box 1)
  - M. von Frey to EBT, in German, 5/12/01 (Box 1)
  - B. H. Blackwell to EBT, 5/17/01 (Box 1)
  - Ed. Montgomery to EBT, 5/19/01 (Box 1)
  - H. W. B. to EBT, 5/21/01 (Box 1)
  - I. (?) Sully to EBT, 5/24/01 (Box 1)
  - Wilson to EBT, 5/21/01 (Box 1)
  - A. Kirschmann to EBT, 5/30/01 (07?) (Box 1)
  - A. F. Hill to EBT, 6/1/01 (Box 1)
  - M. von Frey to EBT, in German, 6/3/01 (Box 1)
  - Dr. Ed. Claparède to EBT, in French, 8/7/01 (Box 1)
  - H. L. W. for Ward's Natural Science Estab., to EBT, 8/16/01 (Box 1)
  - W. Heinenz (?) to EBT, in German (Box 1)
  - 1902 (Box 1)
  - I. (?) Sully to EBT, 1/17/02 (Box 1)
  - Te. L. van Becelaere (?) to EBT, 1/23/02 (Box 1)
  - I. (?) Sully to EBT, 2/20/02 (Box 1)
  - R. Newley (?) to EBT (postcard), 2/24/02 (Box 1)
  - O. Kulpe to EBT, in German, 2/28/02 (Box 1)
  - Wm. Dewey to EBT (postcard), 3/11/02 (Box 1)
  - Max Meyer to EBT (postcard), 3/16/02 (Box 1)
  - Josiah Royce to EBT, 3/29/02 (Box 1)
  - Encl: G. F. Stout to EBT, 3/18/02 (Box 1)
  - O. Kulpe to EBT, in German, 3/31/02 (Box 1)
  - Hugo Munsterberg to EBT, 4/22/02 (Box 1)
  - E. A. Fuertes to EBT, 4/24/02 (Box 1)
  - C. B. Williams for Chicago Laboratory Supply & Scale Co., to EBT, 5/6/02 (Box 1)
  - James R. Angell (?) to EBT, 5/6/02 (Box 1)
  - Margaret- Washburn to EBT, 5/10/02 (Box 1)
  - J. Kairiyanha (?) to EBT, 5/18/02 (Box 1)
  - E. Wheeler Carr to EBT, 5/21/02 (Box 1)
  - K. Marbe to EBT, in German, 5/27/02 (Box 1)
  - James R. Angell to EBT, 6/4/02 (Box 1)
  - Elizabeth Young to EBT, 6/5/02 (Box 1)
  - Encl: Archer Cowley Co. (?) to G. W. Young, 4/10/02 (Box 1)
  - J. E. Creighton, 6/20/02 (Box 1)
  - William Caldwell (?) to EBT, 6/21/02 (Box 1)
  - C. S. Parrish to EBT, 6/29/02 (Box 1)
  - Encl: newspaper clippings (Box 1)
  - W. C. Bagley to EBT, 7/11/02 (Box 1)
  - H. R. Rowland for fencer Lens Co. to EBT, 7/16/02 (Box 1)
  - Gundlach Optical Co., 7/16/02 (Box 1)
  - Encl: Turner Reich Binocular pamphlet (Box 1)
  - Williams, Brown & Earle Opticians to EBT, 7/16/02 (Box 1)
  - Encl: 2 photographs (Box 1)
  - Macmillan Co. Monthly Statement to EBT, 7/28/02 (Box 1)
  - Macmillan Co. Monthly Statement to EBT, 7/31/02 (Box 1)
  - Encl: detailed statements (Box 1)
  - Vitna Welby (?) to EBT, 8/31/02 (Box 1)
  - C. B. Williams for Chicago Lab. to EBT, 8/4/02 (Box 1)
  - W. B. Pillsbury to EBT, 8/7/02 (Box 1)
  - W. C. Bagley to EBT, 9/1/02 (Box 1)
  - Williams, Brown & Earle to EBT, 9/12/02 (Box 1)
  - Encl: Lantern Price List (Box 1)
  - Roswell Park to EBT, 5/5/(02)? (Box 1)
  - 1903 (Box 1)
  - George Trumbell Ladd to EBT, l/4/03 (Box 1)
  - * EBT to Benjamin R. Andrews, 2/19/03 (Box 1)
  - Beaurais to EBT, in French, 5/12/03 (Box 1)
  - W. C. Bagley to EBT, 4/6/03 (Box 1)
  - Macmillan Co. to EBT: Annual Statement, Monthly Statement, Detailed Accounts, 4/30/03 (Box 1)
  - I. K. Funk to EBT, 5/5/03 (Box 1)
  - Encl: Account of finding of mislaid coin, "Widow's Mite" (Box 1)
  - Charles S. Myers to EBT, 5/17/03 (Box 1)
  - Dr. Beaumis to EBT, 6/6/03 French (Box 1)
  - C. B. Williams for Chicago Lab. to EBT, 6/13/03 (Box 1)
  - E. C. Sanford to EBT, 6/24/03 (Box 1)
  - E. C. Sanford to EBT, 8/12/03 (Box 1)
  - E. C. Sanford to EBT (postcard), 8/12/03 (Box 1)
  - C. E. Ferrer to EBT, 8/21/03 (Box 1)
  - ** Robt. Morris Ogden to EBT, 9/18/03 (Box 1)
  - V. Welby to EBT, 9/22/03 (Box 1)
  - Encl: "The Master Paradox" "The Cry of the Starving Brains" (Box 1)
  - J, R. Angell to EBT (postcard), 10/10/03 (Box 1)
  - E. C. Sanford to EBT, 10/13/03 (Box 1)
  - Encl: dummy for journal cover (Box 1)
  - Dr. Ed Claparede to EBT, 10/17/03 (Box 1)
  - Robt. Morris Ogden to EBT, 10/17/03 (Box 1)
  - E. C. Glass to EBT, 10/23/03 (Box 1)
  - C. H. Stoelting for Chicago Lab Supply & Scale Co. to EBT, 10/24/03 (Box 1)
  - * insertions made because add. material received. See Accession sheets. ** Checklist of EBT-RMD corres. in the Ogden Papers, 1/23/67, on file in that ace. folder, with photocopies in the Titchener guide to selected correspondence.^ 4/724. (Box 1)
  - E. S. Williams from Cornell U. Treasurers Offices: Notice of Psychology's Appropriation. beg, Aug. 1, 1903, 10/26/03 (Box 1)
  - Emily J. Conant to EBT, 10/26/03 (Box 1)
  - Benedetto Pergoli to EBT (postcard), 11/16/03 Italian (Box 1)
  - E. C. Glass to EBT, 11/27/03 (Box 1)
  - George I. Brett (?) to EBT, 11/27/03 (Box 1)
  - Robt. Morris Ogden to EBT, 11/28/03 (Box 1)
  - W. P. Garrison for the Nation to EBT, 12/11/03 (Box 1)
  - Williams of C. U. Treasurers office; Notice of appt to EBT, 12/12/03 (Box 1)
  - F. W. Heinentz (?), 12/15/03 German (Box 1)
  - Carnoch (?) to EBT, 12/18/03 (Box 1)
  - EBT to Benjamin R. Andrews, 12/18/03 (Box 1)
  - J. Me. K. Cattell to EBT, 12/19/03 (Box 1)
  - A. D. Waller to EBT, 12/21/03 (Box 1)
  - Christian Ladd Franklin to EBT, 12/22/03 (Box 1)
  - Wilson to EBT, 12/22/03 (Box 1)
  - Henry A. Foster (?) to EBT, 12/22/03 (Box 1)
  - H. J. Bool to EBT, 12/26/03 (Box 1)
  - F. M. Colby to EBT, 12/26/03 (Box 1)
  - 1904 (Box 1)
  - J. Mallet to EBT, 1/3/04 (Box 1)
  - F. M. Colby to EBT, l/4/04 (Box 1)
  - Rev. David Jones to EBT, 1/5/04 (Box 1)
  - End. newspaper clippings (Box 1)
  - W. Rivers to EBT, 1/5/04 (Box 1)
  - E. C. Sanford to EBT, 1/8/04 (Box 1)
  - J. R. Angell (?) to EBT, 1/18/04 (Box 1)
  - * insertions made because add. material rec'd. See Accession Sheets. (Box 1)
  - Edmund C. Sanford to EBT, 1/19/04 (Box 1)
  - A. Kirschmann to EBT, 1/19/04 (Box 1)
  - Max Meyer to EBT, 1/19/04 (Box 1)
  - Charles H. Judd to EBT, 1/20/04 (Box 1)
  - Lightner Witmer to EBT, 1/20/04 (Box 1)
  - MacMillan Company to EBT, 1/21/04 (Box 1)
  - A. H. Pierce to EBT, 1/21/04 (Box 1)
  - Howard C. Warren to EBT, 1/22/04 (Box 1)
  - Win. Bryan to EBT, 1/23/04 (Box 1)
  - James R. Angell to EBT, 1/23/04 (Box 1)
  - W. B. Pillsbury to EBT, 1/23/04 (Box 1)
  - C. E. Seashore to EBT, 1/25/04 (Box 1)
  - J. A. Bergstrom to EBT, 1/25/04 (Box 1)
  - Lightner Witmer to EBT, 1/25/04 (Box 1)
  - Joseph Jastrow to EBT, 1/25/04 (Box 1)
  - Howard C. Warren to EBT, 1/27/04 (Box 1)
  - Hugo Munsterberg to EBT, 1/30/04 (Box 1)
  - G. M. Stratton to EBT, 2/2/04 (Box 1)
  - Hugo Munsterberg to EBT, 2/3/04 (Box 1)
  - E. A. Pace to EBT, 2/4/04 (Box 1)
  - George Lincoln Burr to EBT, 2/6/04 (Box 1)
  - George Lincoln Burr to EBT, 2/9/04 (Box 1)
  - Charles Judd to EBT, 2/9/04 (Box 1)
  - C. E. Seashore to EBT, 2/12/04 (Box 1)
  - James R. Angell to EBT, 2/13/04 (Box 1)
  - E. A. Pace to EBT, 2/16/04 (Box 1)
  - C. A Watson to EBT, 2/17/04 (Box 1)
  - G. M. Stratton to EBT, 2/22/04 (Box 1)
  - Arthur MacDonald to EBT End. Article by MacDonald, 2/22/04 (Box 1)
  - Dodd, Mead & Co. to EBT, 2/27/04 (Box 1)
  - Clara Hart to EBT End. clipping, brochure and letter to C. Hart from H. J. L. J. Masse, 2/27/04 (Box 1)
  - Hugo Milnsterberg to EBT, 2/27/04 (Box 1)
  - Replies to form letter: A. H. Pierce (?) J. M. K. Cattell Max Meyer Edward Thorndike E. B. Delabarre E. C. S. (Edmund C. Sanford) W. B. Pillsbury Wm. H. Bryan John Bergs tram Howard Warren E. H. Lindley, Feb. 1904 (Box 1)
  - Lightner Witraer to EBT, 3/4/04 (Box 1)
  - Kirschraann to EBT, 3/5/04 (Box 1)
  - Charles Von Hise to EBT, 3/11/04 (Box 1)
  - Lightner Witmer to EBT, 3/21/04 (Box 1)
  - Lightner Witmer to EBT, 3/21/04 (Box 1)
  - E. C. S. to EBT, 3/23/04 (Box 1)
  - Charles Judd to EBT, 3/23/04 (Box 1)
  - Max Meyer to EBT, 3/25/04 (Box 1)
  - E. Thorndike to EBT, 3/25/04 (Box 1)
  - W. B. Pillsbury to EBT, 3/25/04 (Box 1)
  - A. H. Pierce to EBT, 3/30/04 (Box 1)
  - A. Meyer to EBT, 5/4/04 (Box 1)
  - James Ward to EBT, 10/3/04 (Box 1)
  - Margaret Schellenberger to EBT, 10/16/04 (Box 1)
  - Benjamin Smith to EBT, 10/22/04 (Box 1)
  - Edmund Huey to EBT, 10/23/04 (Box 1)
  - Mary W. (?) Calkins to EBT, 10/31/04 (Box 1)
  - Unsigned letter from Century Co. to EBT, 11/3/04 (Box 1)
  - Edmund Montgomery to EBT, 11/3/04 (Box 1)
  - E. C. S. to EBT, 11/4/04 (Box 1)
  - Edmund Huey to EBT, 11/4/04 (Box 1)
  - Harris J. Ryan to EBT, 11/13/04 (Box 1)
  - James R. Angell to EBT, 11/14/04 (Box 1)
  - Arthur Pierce to EBT, 11/17/04 (Box 1)
  - Benjamin Smith to EBT, 11/17/04 (Box 1)
  - Macmillan Company to EBT, 11/18/04 (Box 1)
  - James Ward to EBT, 11/28/04 (Box 1)
  - Macmillan Company to EBT, 12/2/04 (Box 1)
  - Benjamin Smith to EBT, 12/10/04 (Box 1)
  - J. McKeen Cattell to EBT, 12/22/04 (Box 1)
  - 1905 (Box 1)
  - EBT to T.A. Hunter (typed cc), 5/13/05 (Box 1)
  - Edward L. Thorndike to EBT, 7/15/05 (Box 1)
  - Charles Herberden to EBT, 9/12/05 (Box 1)
  - Julia Gulliver to EBT, 9/22/05 (Box 1)
  - E. Sanford to EBT, 9/26/05 (Box 1)
  - Joseph Jastrow to EBT, 9/30/05 (Box 1)
  - Edward E. Free (?) to EBT, 10/6/05 (Box 1)
  - E. C. S. to EBT, 10/28/05 (Box 1)
  - James Angell to EBT, 11/1/05 (Box 1)
  - Hugo Munsterberg to EBT, 11/6/05 (Box 1)
  - Edward L. Thorndike to EBT, 11/13/05 (Box 1)
  - W. B. Pillsbury to EBT, 11/14/05 (Box 1)
  - W. B. Pillsbury to EBT, 11/23/05 German (Box 1)
  - Wm. Stone to EBT, 10/5/05 (Box 1)
  - Edward L. Thorndike to EBT, 12/1/05 (Box 1)
  - Macmillan Company to EBT, 12/26/05 (Box 1)
  - 1906 (Box 1)
  - Edwin Watkins to EBT, 2/5/06 (Box 1)
  - David Starr Jordan to EBT, 2/12/06 (Box 1)
  - Benjamin E. Smith to EBT, 2/15/Q6 (Box 1)
  - John B. Watson to EBT, 2/24/06 (Box 1)
  - J. Cattell to EBT, 2/17/06 (Box 1)
  - Edwin Holt to EBT, 3/20/06 (Box 1)
  - W. B. Pillsbury to EBT, 3/23/06 (Box 1)
  - Charles Judd to EBT, 4/7/06 (Box 1)
  - End. map of New Haven (Box 1)
  - ? ? ? to EBT, 4/13/06 German (Box 1)
  - J. E. W. Wallin to EBT, 4/27/06 (Box 1)
  - See February 5, 1906 (Box 1)
  - J. Cattell to EBT, 5/21/06 (Box 1)
  - J. Cattell to EBT, 6/2/06 (Box 1)
  - C. B. Herberden to EBT, 6/9/06 (Box 1)
  - Edward Watkins to EBT, 7/2/06 (Box 1)
  - G, Stanley Hall to EBT, 7/14/06 (Box 1)
  - Edwin H. to EBT, 8/16/06 (Box 1)
  - A. H, Pierce to EBT, 10/11/06 (Box 1)
  - A. H, Pierce to EBT, 10/14/06 (Box 1)
  - Win, Harper David to EBT, 12/11/06 (Box 1)
  - G. B. Moore to EBT, 12/18/06 (Box 1)
  - 1907 (Box 1)
  - E.- C. S. to EBT, 1/12/07 (Box 1)
  - E. L. Sanford to EBT, 1/23/07 (Box 1)
  - EBT to T.A. Hunter (typed cc), 1/24/07 (Box 1)
  - E.C.S. to EBT, 1/30/07 (Box 1)
  - it it n, 2/17/07 (Box 1)
  - Edmund Montgomery to EBT, 3/3/07 (Box 1)
  - E. C. S. to EBT, 3/7/07 (Box 1)
  - E. C. S. to EBT, 3/13/07 (Box 1)
  - EBT to Professor Helder (handwritten copy), 3/14/07 (Box 1)
  - Kirschraann to EBT, 3/21/07 (Box 1)
  - J. W. Baird to EBT, 3/29/07 (Box 1)
  - E. C. S. to EBT, 4/6/07 (Box 1)
  - J. D. L (?) to EBT, 4/25/07 (Box 1)
  - George (?) to EBT, 5/6/07 (Box 1)
  - *EBT to T.A. Hunter (typed cc), 7/15/07 (Box 1)
  - W. B. Pillsbury to EBT, 9/21/07 (Box 1)
  - EBT to T.A. Hunter (typed cc), 9/20/07 (Box 1)
  - 1908 (Box 1)
  - EBT to T.A. Hunter (typed cc), 1/1/08 (Box 1)
  - R. Warren Sailor to EBT, 2/24/08 (Box 1)
  - Benjamin Smith to EBT, 3/2/08 (Box 1)
  - M. Geiger to EBT, 3/6/08 (Box 1)
  - J. W. Baird to EBT, 3/9/08 (Box 1)
  - Whipple to EBT, 3/22/08 (Box 1)
  - MacLennan to EBT, 3/22/08 (Box 1)
  - W. B. Pillsbury to EBT, 3/26/08 (Box 1)
  - E. C. S. to EBT End. Two pages of probability tables, 3/26/08 (Box 1)
  - J. Pease Norton to EBT Encl. pamphlet and postcard, 4/9/08 (Box 1)
  - ? ? ? to EBT., 4/26/08 German (Box 1)
  - Lightner Vlitmer to EBT, 4/2?/08 (Box 1)
  - A. Taylor to EBT, 4/28/08 (Box 1)
  - *Also, letter of recommendation for Hunter to whom it may concern, July 15, 1907, 1 p« (Box 1)
  - *E. B. Holt to EBT, 5/1/08 (Box 1)
  - Mimeograph circular concerning the preparations of Cornell students for the civil service, 5/2/08 (Box 1)
  - W. M. to EBT, 5/2/08 (Box 1)
  - EBT to T.A. Hunter (typed cc), 5/17/08 (Box 1)
  - Dr. Perry to EBT, 5/27/08 (Box 1)
  - James Angell to EBT, 5/29/08 (Box 1)
  - M. Geiger to EBT, 6/6/08 German (Box 1)
  - Charles Finlay to EBT End. brochure from Fletcher Typewriter, 7/21/08 (Box 1)
  - E. C. S. to EBT, 8/9/08 (Box 1)
  - T. A. Hunter to EBT, 8/24/08 (Box 1)
  - Robert M. Yerkes to EBT, 8/2*4708 (Box 1)
  - H. Iffrigram to EBT, 9/3/08 (Box 1)
  - Y. Motora to EBT, 9/10/08 (Box 1)
  - T. Sipps to EBT, 9/15/08 German (Box 1)
  - T. L. Botton to EBT, 9/27/08 (Box 1)
  - S. Alexander to EBT, 9/28/08 (Box 1)
  - L, Murphy to EBT, 10/2/08 (Box 1)
  - J. L. Nerney to EBT, 10/8/08 (Box 1)
  - Raymond Dodge to EBT, 10/9/08 (Box 1)
  - Ann Young to Mr.. Hoy (?), 10/11/08 (Box 1)
  - Macmillan to EBT, 10/16/08 (Box 1)
  - 0. Keelpe to EBT, 10/21/08 German (Box 1)
  - R. Warren Sailor to EBT, 10/25/08 (Box 1)
  - Dr. Ed. Claparede to EBT, 10/25/08 (Box 1)
  - Dean's office to EBT Encl. administrative form, 10/28/08 (Box 1)
  - E. H. Woodruff to EBT, 11/2/08 (Box 1)
  - Robert M. Yerkes to EBT, 11/3/08 (Box 1)
  - Arthur Hadley to EBT, 11/4/08 (Box 1)
  - Stanley Gibbons to EBT, 11/6/08 (Box 1)
  - Cleveland Abbe to EBT, 11/6/08 (Box 1)
  - C. R. Potter to EBT, 11/7/08 (Box 1)
  - A. Harley to EBT, 11/9/08 (Box 1)
  - Goddard to EBT, 11/10/08 (Box 1)
  - Stephen Coloni to EBT, 11/16/08 (Box 1)
  - T. A. Hunter to EBT, 11/18/08 (Box 1)
  - Charles Hughes Johnston to EBT, 11/21/08 (Box 1)
  - James Cattell to EBT, 11/24/08 (Box 1)
  - W. 0. Oldman to EBT End* brochures of guns, knives Receipt to EBT from William Glaisher, 11/26/08 11/27/08 (Box 1)
  - EBT to T.A. Hunter (typed cc), 11/28/08 (Box 1)
  - Printed brochure to EBT from C. B. Heberden, ll/??/08 (Box 1)
  - Form letter to EBT from Charles Judd, 12/2/08 (Box 1)
  - Stanley Gibbons to EBT, 12/4/08 (Box 1)
  - Dean to W. A. Hammond, 12/4/08 (Box 1)
  - John Britnell to EBT, 12/8/08 (Box 1)
  - Stephen Coloni to EBT, 12/10/08 (Box 1)
  - W. C. Ramsay to EBT, 12/11/08 (Box 1)
  - Edward Nichols to EBT, 12/12/08 (Box 1)
  - J. W. Baird to EBT, 12/13/08 (Box 1)
  - John B. Watson to EBT, 12/14/08 (Box 1)
  - T. Sakri to EBT, 12/17/08 (Box 1)
  - Watson to EBT, 12/l9/08 (Box 1)
  - Charles Josser to EBT Encl. brochure from Cambridge Scientific Instrument Company, 12/22/08 (Box 1)
  - Cleveland Abbe to EBT, 12/22/08 (Box 1)
  - E. C. S. to EBT, 12/28/08 (Box 1)
  - Mrs.. C. W. Albany, 1908 (?) (Box 1)
  - R. R. Gurley to EBT, 2/24/08 (Box 1)
  - 1909 (Box 2)
  - Charles Hull to EBT, 1/4/09 (Box 2)
  - K B. Holt to EBT, 1/8/09 (Box 2)
  - C. B. Herberden to EBT End. Brosenose College brochure, 1/9/09 (Box 2)
  - J. Mark Baldwin to EBT, 1/12/09 (Box 2)
  - J. H. Leuba (?) to EBT, 1/12/09 (Box 2)
  - J. Cattell to EBT, 1/13/09 (Box 2)
  - Stephen Coloni to EBT, 1/16/09 (Box 2)
  - Yerkes to EBT, 1/16/09 (Box 2)
  - J. Cattell to EBT, 1/18/09 (Box 2)
  - J. W. Baird to EBT, 1/24/09 (Box 2)
  - C. D. Bostwick to EBT, 1/26/09 (Box 2)
  - Farmers Week to EBT Encl. letter from Martha Van Renssalaer and two brochures, 2/1/09 (Box 2)
  - C. D. Bostwick to EBT, 2/2/09 (Box 2)
  - J. G. Schurman to EBT, 2/4/09 (Box 2)
  - T. A. Hunter to EBT, 2/6/09 (Box 2)
  - Cleveland Abbe to EBT, 2/6/09 (Box 2)
  - C. S. Srasliong (?) to EBT, 2/9/09 (Box 2)
  - G. Stanley Hall to EBT, 2/10/09 (Box 2)
  - Robert M. Yerkes to EBT, 2/11/09 (Box 2)
  - Howard C. Warren to EBT, 2/12/09 (Box 2)
  - Macmillan Company to EBT, 2/18/09 (Box 2)
  - J. F. Stout to EBT, 2/20/09 (Box 2)
  - J. W. Baird to EBT, 2/28/09 (Box 2)
  - Charles Judd to EBT Encl. Mist of scholarly journals, 3/4/09 (Box 2)
  - L. B. H. H. to EBT, 3/6/09 (Box 2)
  - H. W. Carr to EBT, 3/8/09 (Box 2)
  - J. H. Coffin to EBT, 3/13/09 (Box 2)
  - Macraillan Company to EBT, 3/16/09 (Box 2)